Domenic Di Francesco, CEng (MIMechE)

RESEARCH ENGINEER

☑ domenicdifrancesco@gmail.com | 😭 allyourbayes.com | 🖸 DomDF | 🛅 domenic-di-francesco-ceng-821792a2

Summary_

Chartered engineer with professional experience in consultancies within the oil and gas engineering industry, working in technical and client-facing roles. Passionate about developing and communicating quantitative decision support tools for industry. Currently completing a PhD focused on applied Bayesian statistics to quantify and propagate multi-variate uncertainty through multi-stage decision analyses. This research has built on guidance in existing industrial codes and standards.

Qualifications _____

PHD, Bayesian Decision Analysis in Structural Integrity Management

Currently completing an industrially funded PhD project. The work is primarily completed at the National Structural Integrity Research Centre (NSIRC) with industrial sponsorship and supervision from Lloyd's Register Foundation and academic supervision from Aalborg Universitet (Denmark) and the University of Surrey (UK).

Peer-Reviewed (First Author) Journal Publications and Conference Papers

- 'Consistent Treatment of Uncertainties and Dependencies in Fatigue Crack Growth Calculations Using Multi-Level Bayesian Models', Journal of Reliability Engineering and System Safety, Vol. 204, Dec. 2020 *link*.
- 'Evaluation of Inspection Features Including Exposure Risk Using a Value of Information Analysis', Submitted to Journal of Civil Engineering and Environmental Systems, under review.
- 'Bayesian Multi-Level Modelling for Improved Prediction of Corrosion Growth Rate Using Limited Data', Conference Paper & Presentation, 39th International Conference on Ocean, Offshore and Arctic Engineering, OMAE2020.
- 'Improved Estimation of Fatigue Crack Growth Rate by Partial Pooling of Test Data in Bayesian Models', Conference Abstract & Presentation, NSIRC Conference 2020.
- 'Inspection Planning of Hazardous Locations Using a Value of Information Analysis', Conference Paper & Presentation, 11th International Forum on Engineering Decision Making, IFED2019.
- 'Bayesian Fatigue Modelling: Application of Markov Chain Monte Carlo Sampling to Account for Variability and Dependency', Conference Paper & Presentation, 17th International Probabilistic Workshop, IPW2019.

MENG, Mechanical Engineering

Durham University, 2.1 (Hons)

Research project in 'Mechanical Characterisation of Ultra-High Molecular Weight Polyethylene (UHMWPE)'.

Professional Experience _

SENIOR ENGINEER, PENSPEN LTD.

2014 - 2017, Pipeline integrity engineer from 2014 - 2016

Delivering technical studies and training to international oil and gas operators based on guidance in relevant codes & standards. Managing client relationships, reviewing work from junior engineers.

GRADUATE INTEGRITY ENGINEER, DNVGL

2012 - 2014

Delivery of a software project for the risk-based integrity management of onshore coal seam gas pipelines in Australia. This included several long-term site-based secondments with the operator.

PRAKTIKANT (ENGINEERING INTERNSHIP), ALSTOM

2010 - 2011

Working in auxiliary systems for gas turbine power plant projects. Creation of an air-intake system selection calculation tool.

Skills

PROGRAMMING

R

Statistic programming environment. Used for data analysis, visualisation, and evaluating statistical models. I am particularly familiar with the following packages:

- tidyverse: for transforming data and visualisation, see link to examples
- tidymodels: for fitting and evaluating machine learning models.
- RMarkdown: for producing live reports, which can readily be updated with new analysis.
- RStan: for pre-processing data, and extracting results from Bayesian models written in Stan (see below).
- loo: for various evaluation methods of probabilistic models.
- shiny for creating web-based, dynamic dashboards.

Python

High level language used for object oriented programming. I am particularly familiar with the following packages:

- · Pandas: for transforming data.
- NumPy: for manipulating data arrays..
- Scikit-Learn: for fitting and evaluating machine learning models.
- PyStan: for pre-processing data, and extracting results from Bayesian models written in Stan (see below).

Stan

Stan is a probabilistic programming language for Bayesian inference. It runs a state of the art Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling algorithm, suitable for high dimensional and multi-level models.

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

As a senior engineer I was responsible for writing technical and commercial proposals, and managing awarded projects through to completion, ensuring work was delivered on time, within budget, and in accordance with quality assurance procedures. Managed new and long-term client relationships, and presented regularly to both technical and non-technical representatives.

BAYESIAN STATISTICS

My PhD research has investigated how Bayesian statistics can be used to improve risk-based structural integrity management. I have demonstrated industrial application of methods such as **quantification of the value of information** (preposterior decision analysis) for inspection activities and **partial pooling of information** from inspection and testing datasets, using multi-level Bayesian models.

Additional Courses and Training

I have also completed the below training courses to further develop my analytical and modelling skills:

SHORT TERM SCIENTIFIC MISSION (STSM)

Aalborg University, February 2019

BAYESIAN INFERENCE USING RSTAN

Jumping Rivers, December 2018

ADVANCED COURSE ON SYSTEMS RISK MODELLING AND ANALYSIS IN ENGINEERING DECISION MAKING

Joint Committee on Structural Safety (JCSS), May 2018

TRAINING SCHOOL ON QUANTIFICATION ON THE VALUE OF STRUCTURAL HEALTH MONITORING

COST Action TU 1402, November 2017

SHEFFIELD FRACTURE MECHANICS

Fracture Training Associates, 2015